Adam Filchoir

Address - Kepulauan Riau, Batam City, Indonesia 29432

Mobile - (+60) 016-8117523 •

LinkedIn - https://www.linkedin.com/in/adamadamadam/ •

Email - filchoiradam@gmail.com



SUMMARY

In the book *Meditations by Marcus Aurelius*, he says "Waste no more time arguing what a good man should be". There's an endless discussion on what a good man is, but It is not what we say that defines them, but what we do. My name is Adam Filchoir, a Computer Science student from Asia Pacific University, there I aim to be active in communities, clubs, volunteering, even joined a few competitions around campus and was able to win some. A humanitarian and a reader at heart. Academically sufficient with an enjoyment for coding. an Interest in Web-Dev and AI. There is much I can improve on to be a good man or perhaps, candidate. The next words from Marcus assures that it all begins we our will, so he says, the best you can, to "Be One".

EDUCATION

Asia Pacific University of Technology and Innovation

Kuala Lumpur, Taman Teknologi

Bachelor's Degree in Computer Science September 2020 - September of 2023

- 1st Year CGPA: 3.67 | 2nd Year CGPA: 3.52 | 3rd Year CGPA: 3.49
- Active in various clubs including, Enterprise Club, IEEE Club, Finance club, CREDIT Centre for Research and Development of IoT member.
- Volunteered in multiple events to be more included in the campus community.

WORKING EXPERIENCE

Software Developer

(CREDIT) Centre for Research and Development of IoT

March 2023 - Present

• Software expert of the research center filled with Engineering students. Research and Develops using new technology for new projects used within manufacturing and production. Full Stack Engineer developing Mobile Apps

Quality Assurance Tester Internship

ISATEC SDN BHD

August 2022 – November 2022

• Performing functionality testing and preparation of test scripts for a large scale project. Familiarized with software tools for efficiency. Consistently being meticulous and detailed regarding test subjects. Self Initiatied.

VOLUNTEERING EXPERIENCE

The Giving Bank Humanitarian Volunteer

The Giving Bank Organization

June 2022 - Present

 Going to regular Humanitarian Events to help the community. Primarily going to Orphanages, Schools Participates in Leadership Programs. Since 2022, Joined approximately 20 Humanitarian Missions entertaining kids and elderlies around Kuala Lumpur. Missions are filled with different tasks and activities to be prepared before the day with various volunteers from around the world.

Health Screening Personnel Volunteer

Campus Hope

June 2022- Present

• Assistend in hosting and organizing a Health Screening around KL and on Campus. Varies from 1 day or within a span of 2 Days. Had served a total of more than 700 patients across multiple events. Capable of being assigned a health station. Understood on how to advice patients to better their lifestyle.

Virtual GameFest 2021 Moderator

Asia Pacific University of Technology and Innovation

February 2021 – March 2021

• Smoothly moderated a seminar with various speakers from companies regarding Game Development Technology. Hosted using StreamYard and broadcasted on YouTube and Facebook, tasked to manage the flow of the interview session and the comment section.

Teaching Assistant

Sekolah Global Indo Asia

January 2018 – January 2020

• Taught and tutored juniors Cambridge Assessment in ICT every week. Dedicated our Saturdays to assist our teacher in educating their students. Resulted in 80% of the students getting an A+ and 100% above a B.

SOCIETIES

Campus Hope Club

Asia Pacific University of Technology and Innovation

Committee Member

May 2022 - Present

• A social club for students to promote mental health and physical health of students. In charge of organizing and planning of Weekly Sports and Activities for members of the club.

CERTIFICATION AND AWARDS

ITEX Innovation Expo

(CREDIT) Centre for Research and Development of IoT

Silver Medal

May 2023

• The proposed idea is a Computer Vision Hub solution for Defect Detection and identify PPE hazards around and in the manufacture. Developed an application to populate with the records of defects and hazards along with the Industrial metaverse of the factory.

Outstanding Volunteer Awardee

The Giving Bank Foundation

Second Best Volunteer

December 2022

• Actively participated in monthly volunteering efforts around Kuala Lumpur. Participation was noticed and awarded for being a highly active and constantly putting on a smile.

Battle of Minds 2022

British American Tobacco

Top 5 Finalist

July 2022

• Pitched a Startup Company about fashion and the use of computer vision within a certain time frame, using a developed prototype and understanding various ways to gain revenue and gather investors.

StartUp Weekend @ APU

Asia Pacific University of Technology and Innovation

1st Runner Up

March 2022

• Pitched a Startup Company about fashion and the use of computer vision within a certain time frame, using a developed prototype and understanding various ways to gain revenue and gather investors.

Substrate Programme Mini Hackathon

Octopus Network

1st Place Winner

May 2022

 Worked using Substrate Library on Rust Language to propose a Recruitment and Job Application Platform Program using Smart Contracts and Tokens

Sakura Science Program

Japan Science and Technology Agency (JST)

Scholarship Program

October 2019

• Awarded a Scholarship program to travel to Kyutech in Kyushu, Japan. Toured campus and given multiple workshops regarding Robotics, Machinery and Chatbot Technology.